Jeremy Kahne

Senior Developer, Dev Manager, Team Leader



jkahne@gmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeremykahne/

SUMMARY

I have 20 years of experience discovering, building, learning, and iterating on products, process, and business initiatives. I am an advocate for, and prefer to work with, self-managing agile teams in which developers, designers, and product owners work collaboratively to solve underlying challenges and afford opportunities to end users. I can talk product strategy with the C-suite or roll up my sleeves and write production level Rails, Phoenix, React, or even SQL. Intangibly, the team culture is very important to me. I work hard so that everyone can bring their best self to work and that departments are aligned with a constancy of purpose.

EXPERTISE

Product Disco	very Prod	luct Delivery	Team Leadership	Technical Leadership		Project Management		
Continuous Improvement		Mentorship	Outcome Based	Product Sense	Systemic Thinker		Pair Programming	

EXPERIENCE

GASLIGHT 2016 - 2020

Dev Manager, Consultant, Team Lead, Senior Developer

- Provided technical delivery daily (mostly pair programming), facilitated standups, and provided guidance to client stakeholders on project status, outcomes, and expectations.
- Performed project kickoffs and discovery, story mapping, release plans, retrospectives, and strategic planning for the product with product owners and client stakeholders.
- Performed weekly 1-on-1s with juniors and peers that focused on career development, consulting, outward mindset, etc.
- Started and ran a book club to help peers grow as consultants and leaders. Provided coaching sessions to aspiring team leads. Ran Ruby on Rails workshops for junior teammates.
- Participated in hiring (meet & greets and pairing sessions).

Clients:

FRAYT Technologies - Cincinnati-based tech start-up that offers a platform to facilitate arrangement of pick-up and delivery services.

- Replaced a no-code backend with an Elixir/Phoenix server to handle increased load and stabilize performance.
- Mentored FRAYT development team in Elixir and Phoenix, TDD, and Agile and Lean practices.
- Implemented 3rd party integrations (Slack, OneSignal, Stripe, Google Maps and Address Lookup, Amazon S3).
- Technologies used: Elixir, Phoenix, ExUnit, PostgreSQL, PostGIS, Github Actions, Git, S3.

Chegg – provides digital and physical textbook rentals, online tutoring, and other student services.

- Wrote frontend React app to allow current and prospective students to interactively evaluate projected post-graduation financial outcomes given inputs of selected school, major, location, and position.
- 3rd party integrations: Recharts for real-time 10 year projections for potential salary & savings and Google Maps to show geographic visualizations of results.
- Technologies used: React (hooks), Redux, Axios, Recharts, Cypress, Git.

Fern Exposition Services - delivers personalized trade shows and conferences to over 1400 event organizers.

- Built E-Commerce platform and Task manager to create an industry-first store that allows teams to work collaboratively and easily navigate trade show preparations.
- Rails API backend extended Solidus E-Commerce platform to add additional functionality such as team-based bookmarks and shopping carts, promotions, discounts, custom labor products with costs based on day of week and time of day, and custom calculators for highly flexible variants of products.
- Designed and implemented reusable components for functionality in React throughout application.
- Technologies used: Ruby on Rails, Sidekiq, RSpec, React, Axios, Solidus, PostgreSQL, Heroku, S3, Git, Codeship.

OMEGA Processing Solutions - premium electronic payment processing provider and B2B eCommerce solution.

- Created a customized CRM for representatives to use on Surface tablets to increase efficiency of sales cycle, with sales pipeline, calendar, proposal calculator, integrated digital signature, notifications, and report modules.
- Reduced sales cycle for average first-appointment-to-close metric from 25 days to 5 days.
- Technologies used: Ruby on Rails, Sidekiq, RSpec, React, Redux, Axios, HelloSign, PostgreSQL, Heroku, S3, Git, Codeship.

Senior Software Developer

- Created a new role-based workflow (called PIC3) for workers in the field to increase items processed from 8 items/hour to 19 items/hour (avg). PIC3 is a system to create and manage sales and items, upload images, edit and review descriptions, and prepare the sale before going live.
- Overhauled categorizations on ebth.com to enable multi-leveled nested hierarchies and many-to-many relationships to items. Implemented via closure table to optimize for read queries.
- Participated in code reviews, fixing bugs, UI and UX discussion and implementation, meeting with stakeholders as necessary to discuss new features and directions.
- Technologies used: Ruby on Rails, Sidekiq, JQuery, SASS, MariaDB, Minitest, Git.

SQRL 2014 - 2015

Senior Software Developer

- Took responsibility of creating and maintaining RESTful JSON APIs using Ruby on Rails, which were consumed by a front end javascript applications.
- Took responsibility to stabilize product and increase maintainability. Added a Minitest test suite, removed many N+1 queries, fixed many bugs and inconsistencies, and added Postgres indices.
- Integrated with the DocuSign API to enable e-signatures for 8879 tax forms.
- · Technologies used: Ruby on Rails, Sidekiq, Redis, React, Heroku, Postgres, Minitest, Git.

SCRIP-SAFE 2011 - 2014

Chief Technology Officer, Senior Software Developer

- Key member of executive team; responsible for product management, engineering, data & IT functions as well as customer installations, customizations, and user support.
- Provide executive leadership and direction for all B2C and B2B services that securely processes electronic transcripts and diplomas driving over \$7 million in annual revenue across 2500+ universities.
- Championed and guided an agile transformation in effort to get executive team, department heads, and teams aligned in purpose.
- Implemented kanban boards, continuous integration, frequent deployments, and a/b testing via feature flags.
- Maintained the technical proficiency and quality of code via test-driven development.
- Vastly improved uptime measures (97.6% to 99.9%), deployment frequency (every 2 weeks to multiple times a day), and lead time for features, as well as decreased Mean Time To Restore (MTTR).
- Organized and oversaw logistics for the migration of 12 servers to a new datacenter.
- Mentored developers and delegate tasks as appropriate to grow their abilities.
- Standardized toolsets across multiple applications, including: queuing mechanism from homegrown to Sidekiq, centralized reporting service, upgrade all applications to supported versions of Ruby/Rails.
- Collaboratively created a new queue-based PDF processor written in JRuby. This resulted in a more flexible, resilient, and fault tolerant architecture.
- Technologies used: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, JRuby, Git, Sidekiq, Redis, Capistrano, Mina, Minitest, iText.

NIMBLE RIVER, LLC 2010 – Present (Inactive)

Owner/ Principal Consultant

Client: Miami University: Project Dragonfly: 2011

• Wrote an Adobe Flex 3 application for the Cincinnati Zoo's "Night Hunters Exhibit" as part of the NSF funded project 'Saving Species' that allowed young guests to create a digital postcard with Big Cat content on a touch screen and share via email, Facebook or Twitter.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science / Computer Science / Mathematics

Art and Design minor summa cum laude Muskingum University, New Concord, OH 1998 – 2002